集まってもらってすみません！
Sorry for making you guys come!
どうしたの、マーゲイ？
What's the matter, Margay?
今日はオフの日だって。
I thought today was an off day.
何かあれば、お手伝いしますよ。
We'll help you out if you need it.
えーっとですね…
Well, you see...
ハカセ達から頼まれまして、一つお仕事をお願いしたいんです。
I'd like to ask your assistance in a favor from the owls.
直々にとは珍しいな。どんな仕事なんだ？
It's rare for them to be so personal. What kind of favor?
ジャパリまんを百個！
We need to provide 100 Japari buns!
できれば、二百個以上用意して欲しいとのことです。
More than 200, if possible.
ジャパリまん～
Japari buns~
フルル、食べてんじゃねぇよ…
Hululu, we're not eating..
あ、かばんさんが今度、旅に出るから？
Ah, is this for Kaban-san's journey?
ん？それって、ボスが用意させたんじゃなかったか？
Huh? Didn't Boss prepare that for her?
あれよ、コウテイ！サーバルが付いて行くでしょう？
Isn't Serval following along? That must be it!
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
あいつ、自分で食べ物取れずに、飢え死にしそうだもんな…
Not bringing along her own food... she'll die of starvation.
大体この袋いっぱいで、二百個らしいです！
We need to prepare 200 buns, just about enough to fill this sack!
お願いできますか？
Can you girls do it?
分かりました！
Got it!
百個…結構な量よね…
100 buns... that's quite the amount.
ボスは食べる分しかくれねぇしなぁ…
But Boss only gives us as much as we need to eat...
精々五、六個だよな？
About 5, 6 buns at the most.
何か当てがあればいいのだが…
If only there was something we could rely on...
プリンセス、島にそういう所ってないか？
Princess, is there a place for that somewhere in this island?
噂で、ボスがジャパリまんを作っている場所があるって、聞いたことあるけど…
Well, I heard rumors that there is a place where Boss makes Japari Buns...
ああ、私も聞いたことあります、でも誰も見たことないんですよね。
Ah! I've also heard that. But no one's ever actually seen it...
まさにハカセが、
It must be that
「そこに行ってちょいちょいしてくるのです」、と！
the professor wants us to "go real quick and do it for us".
ええ？
Ehh!?
まあ、この先食べる分には変わりないから、前以て貰う感じか。
Well, it's not like the amount they're eating will change in the future. It'll be like getting it in advance.
それって、どこにあるんだ？
Well, where is it?
それが、
Well, they said,
「では頼んだですよ。我々忙しいのです。」
"We're leaving the rest to you. We are busy."
「ハカセ。行きましょう。じゅるり。」
"Let us go, professor. Slurp."
「行きますか、ジョシュ。じゅるり。」、と。
"Let us go, assistant. Slurp."
丸投げかよ！
They're dumping it all on us?!
あの二人、本当に忙しいのか？
Are those two actually busy?
うぅぅ…他のフレンズに聞いてみましょうか！
Hrmm... Let's go ask other Friends!
サーバル達のためだ。頑張ろう！
It's for Serval and Kaban. Let's do our best!
何人か聞いてみたけど、誰も知らないわね。
We asked a bunch of Friends, but none of them knew.
みんな自分の縄張りの外は、そこまで詳しくないからなぁ。
Well, they wouldn't know about much outside of their territory...
あれ？PPPのみんな、どうしたの？
Hm? Hey, PPP, what's the matter?
こんにちは！この前はありがとうございました。
Hello! Thanks for your help last time.
いえいえかばんさん、こちらこそ！
Not at all, Kaban-san. We owe it to you as well.
お元気そうで何よりです。
We're glad that you're fine.
よう、サーバル。今ジャパリまんを探しててな！
Yo, Serval! We're looking for Japari buns.
へぇ、なんでなんで？何かやるの？
Huh! Why; what are you guys doing?
それはね、サーバルがかばんちゃんに付いて行く時に…
It's for when you're going to follow Kaban...
ちょ、ちょ、ちょっと事情があってさ…
W-Well, we have our reasons...
それで、ジャパリまんを作ってる所を探してるの！
And so we're looking for where Japari buns are made!
ボスが作ってる所があるらしいんだけど、誰も知らないんだ。
Supposedly there's a place where Boss makes them, but no one knows where it is.
そうなんだ。あたしも知らないな。
I see. I don't know either...
かばんちゃん、何かいい案ないかな？
Kaban-chan, do you have any idea?
そうだ！ジャパリまんを配ってるラッキーさん、
I know! When Lucky-san has no more Japari buns to distribute,
籠が空になったら新しいのを取りに行くだろうから、
it'll go back to fetch some more;
それに付いて行ってみる！ってどうでしょう。
Let's try to follow it!
なるほど！
I see!
かばんはさすがだな！
You're amazing as usual, Kaban.
早速探すわよ！
Let's go find one now!
おぅー！
Yeah!
よく分からないけど、力になれたｘよかった。
I don't really get it, but I'm glad I was able to help out.
私達も遊びに行こう！
Let's also go and have some fun!
あ、アリツカゲラが寝床の見つけ方を教えてくれるって言ってたよ！
Oh yeah, Campo Flick said she would teach us how to find a place to sleep!
行ってみない？
Wanna go?
うん！
Yeah!
ボス、ボス…
Boss... Boss...
籠を持ったボス…
A Boss with a basket...
いつもジャパリまんがなくなった頃にふらっと現れるんだよなぁ。
He always appears out of nowhere when we're out of Japari buns...
いたわよ！
There it is!
ちょうどフレンズが貰いに来てますね。
It seems like a bunch of Friends have just come to get them.
残り、あと二、三個ぐらいか。
There's about 2 or 3 buns left.
いいなぁ、あたしも食べたいなぁ…
Aww, I want some too...
お前、さっき喰ってなかったか？
Didn't you already eat just now?
ああ！なくなりましたよ！
Ah! There's no more!
どうするのかしら…
What shall we do...
考えた事がなかったなぁ。
We didn't think about that, did we...
歩き始めたぜ。
He's started to move.
追いかけましょう！
Let's follow it!
うう…この体とは言え、
Urgh... it's actually pretty hard
ぼこぼこした所を歩くのは、苦手だ…
to walk on rough paths in this body...
そう？
Is that so?
無理しちゃダメよ、コウテイ
Don't push yourself too hard, Emperor.
ボスを見失わないようにしないとな！
We can't lose sight of Boss!
あ！何か見えてきましたよ。
Ah! I see something.
崖に穴が…
There's a hole in the cliff...
トンネルかしら?
Is it a tunnel?
入口の左右に、別のボスがいますね。
There are other Bosses around the entrance.
籠持ったボスが、中に入ってくぞ！
A Boss with a basket is entering!
追いかけましょう！
Let's follow it!
な、何？なんで邪魔するの？
H-huh? Why are you obstructing me?
ボス、怒ってますね。
It looks like Boss is angry.
ちょ、ちょっと離れるわよ。
I-I'll move farther away.
どうしようか。
What do we do?
ちょっと、無理して間を取ってみるか？
でもよ、ボスを怒らせると、追いかける所じゃなくなるぜ。
ボスとお話できるかばんさんに、説得をお願いしてみますか？
Kaban-san can talk to Bosses. Should we try and ask her to persuade Boss?
でも、サーバルが付いて行くことはまだ内緒にしてあげなくちゃ…
But then, we have to keep secret the fact that Serval is tagging along...
あまり話したらバレちゃうわよ。
If we say too much, she'll find out.
よ！
Yo!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
かさ…こそ。
Rustle...rustle.
かさ、こそ、かさ…
Rustle, rustle, rustle...
へぇ？
Huh?
ジャイアント先輩！？
Giant-senpai!?
何だ？まだ見つかってないのか？ジャパリまん。
What? Haven't you girls found any Japari buns yet?
そうなの…
No, not yet...
っていうか、なんでそれを知ってるんですか？
But how on earth did you know?
相変わらず、謎の多い…
Mysterious, as always...
しっしっしっし。
Hehehe.
それが、あそこの入口からボスが入れてくれなくて…
Well, the Bosses won't let us in through the entrance over there...
なるほどな。
I seel.
じゃあ、ラッキービーストの前で心底困ってるふりをしてみろ。
How about pretending to be sincerely troubled in front of Lucky Beast?
困ってるふり？
Pretending to be troubled?
あいつは人しか助けないわけじゃない。
It's not that that thing helps people only.
なんだかんだ困ってるフレンズがいると、サポートするんだ。
Boss'll support Friends who are troubled about this and that.
へぇー。
Huh.
じゃあな。
See ya!
まあ、うまくやりなー。がさごそがさごそ。
Well, try to do well. Rustle, rustle, rustle.
何だったんだ？
What was that about?
あの先輩の言う事は、なんだかんだ当たるｘ。
やってみましょう！
Let's try it!
よう、ボス！
Yo, Boss!
さらにロックなｘをするために、
そこを通してほしいんだ！
I want to enter!
えっ。
Uh, well...
ロックってのはその…
By "rock" I mean...
ほら、岸壁、とかさぁ、
You know, like cliffs, things like that...
困難を…
Or rather, only by...
越えてこそ、っていうか…
conquering hardships... or something...
ダメだ。
It's no use.
ボス怖ぇよ…
Boss is too scary...
よしよしー。
There, there.
次は、私が行こう。
I'll go next.
えっとだな、ボス。
Well, um, Boss.
困ってるんだ。
I need your help.
私は、その。
I, uh...
気絶してるー！
She's passed out!
ダメだ。
It's no use.
ブリザードのような目だ。
Her eyes are like a blizzard.
よしよしー。
There, there.
ジェーン？
Gen?
ボス、私達、助けたい子がいて、
Boss, there's a girl we want to help.
そのためにジャパリまんが必要なんです。
In order to do that, we need Japari buns.
どうかそこ、通してもらえませんか？
Please, could you let us through?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
えぇ！？
Huh!?
ジェーン、すごーい！
Gen, you're awesome!
さっすがね、ジェーン！
Nice one, Gen!
正直が一番、と言う事か。
I guess "honesty is the best policy", eh?
出口から光が射してるけど、
There's light coming from the exit,
薄暗いわね。
but it's still pretty dark, huh.
いっ、てっ…
Ow...!
イワビーさん、跳ねたら頭をぶつけますよ。
You'll hit your head if you jump in here, Iwabi-san.
ゆっくり歩きましょう。
Let's walk slowly.
見えてきたわ。
I can see it now.
うわぁー。
Wow...
大きい池ですね。
What a huge lake.
パークにこんな所があったなんて…
For a place like this to exist in the park...
島があるね。
There's an island.
ボスは、あそこだろうか。
Maybe that's where Boss is.
行こう。
Let's go.
不思議な所だな。
What a mysterious place.
木漏れ日が気持ちいいですね。
The sunlight through the trees feels nice.
あ！見て！
Ah! Look over there!
木にジャパリまんがぶら下がってる！
Japari buns are hanging from the trees!
しかも、すげぇ沢山あるぞ。
And there's a lot too.
どう言う事だ？
What could it mean?
ジャパリまんって、木に生るのか？
Do Japari buns grow on trees?
あ！ボスですよ！
Ah! Bosses!
ジャパリまんの束を投げて、木に引っ掛けてるぜ。
They're throwing bunches of Japari buns into the trees and letting them hang.
なにしてるのかしら。
What are they doing?
キラキラして綺麗ー。
It's shiny and pretty.
行っちゃいましたね。
They left.
あれは、どこから持ってきたんだろうか。
Where did they bring it here from?
チャンスだぜ。
Now's our chance.
ここにあるやつを、貰って行こう！
Let's go get the ones here!
そうね。行きましょう！
You're right. Let's go!
これは…
This is...
なかなか大変だな。
quite a tough job.
こういう細かい作業、未だに苦手なんだよなぁ。
I'm still not good at such precise work yet...
あの子達のために、少しでも多めに用意してあげないと…
We have to prepare a decent amount for those girls, if even a little bit.
島の外に、食べ物があるか分からないもの！
We don't know if there's anything to eat outside of the island!
早くしないと、またボスが来そうですね。
If we don't hurry up, Boss will come back.
よ、よ、よ、よ、よ、よ、よ、よ…
Heave-ho, heave-ho- heave-ho.
すげぇ速いなぁ！
Man, she's fast!
フルル、ジャパリまんの事になると動きが…
When it comes to Japari buns, Hululu'll work faster...
すごいですね。一人で百個ぐらい集めてるんじゃないですか。
Amazing. She's collected about 100 all by herself.
ああ！ボスが！
Ah! Bosses!
ヤバい、見つかった！
Shoot, they've spotted us!
に、逃げましょう！
L-let's make a run for it!
どうしましょう？どんどん増えてきてますよ！
What do we do? More of them are coming!
ひぃー！すごい怒ってるぜ！
Eek! They're really furious!
泳いで逃げよう！池に飛び込むぞ！
Let's get away by swimming. Jump into the lake!
えぇーい！
Alley oop!
やっぱり水の中は落ち着くわね。
In the end, the water is pretty soothing, huh.
よし。距離を稼ごう。
Alright. Let's gather distance.
ふん！
Mm!
ジェーン相変わらず速ーい。
Gen is fast as always~.
行くぜ行くぜ！
Let's go, let's go!
イワビー相変わらず速ーい。
Iwabi is fast as always~.
よし。大分撒いたな。
Alright. We've shaken them off.
このまま一気に出口まで！
Let's keep this pace all the way to the exit!
トンネルの中からもボスが！
There are more Bosses coming from the tunnel too!
うっ、うぅえ…
U, uurgh...
どうしよう？後ろからも沢山来ますよ。
What do we do? There's a bunch of them coming from behind too.
ひぃー！ダメだ！
Eek! It's hopeless!
くっ…ここまでなの？
Darn! Is this the end?
わっせ、わっせ、わっせ、わっせ…
一番乗りなのだ！
We're the first to arrive!
うっ。
Oof.
え？
Eh?
何？
What?
なんだ、なんだ？
What is it? What is it?
真ん丸はどこにあるのだ！
Where's the round thing!
どこなのだ！
Where is it!
あれー？今は何かにぶつかったようなー…
Huh? It seems like we hit something just right now...
あなた達は確か…
You guys are...
アライさんなのだ！
I'm Arai-san!
フェネクスなのさー。
I'm Fennec.
わぁ、何これ。
Wow, what is that?
ふっふーん。これは、「ばすてき」って言うのだ！
Heheh. It's a "bus-ish"!
ハカセに貰ったのだ！
The Professor gave it to us!
へぇ。
Hmm.
わ…わ…
あ。アライさん、大変だよー。
Ah. Bad news, Arai-san.
どうやらボスを撥ねちゃったみたいだねー。
It seems like we hit a Boss.
え？あ！へぇ！？
Huh? Ah! What!?
ご、ご、ごめんなさいなのだ、ボス！
I-I-I'm sorry, Boss!
体は大丈夫みたいだねー。
It seems like their body is okay.
でも、なんか怒ってるから逃げようかー。
But they seem kind of angry. Let's get away.
ひぃー！？
Eek!
わっせ、わっせ、わっせ、わっせ、わっせ、わっせ、わっせ…
速い、速ーい。
Wow, so fast~.
助かったわ！
You saved us!
二人は、どうしてここに？
So, what are you two doing here?
こーんな格好の子がー、
A girl who looked kind of like this
ここに私達の探し物があるって言ってたからー…
said that the thing we're looking for would be somewhere around here...
真ん丸がなかったのだ！
There was no round thing!
騙されたのだ！
She tricked us!
ジャイアント先輩だ…
It must be Giant-senpai...
全部お見通し、って事ね…
She saw it all coming, didn't she...?
あの人怖ぇよ…
Man, she's creepy...
取り敢えずよかった、ですかね。
Well, we're okay for now, I suppose.
よくないのだ！
It's not okay!
真ん丸がなかったのだ！
There's no round thing!
まあ、まあ。
Now, now.
結果オーライでフレンズ助けになったっぽいよー。
We got out alright and helped out some Friends.
オーラくないのだ！
It's not alright!
アライさんの今後の危機なのだ！
Arai-san's future is in danger!
お、お疲れ様でしたー！
Thank you all so much for your hard work!
もー、めっちゃめっちゃ怖かったわよ！
Man, it was scary!
いやー、歩いた泳いだ！
Ahh, we had a nice walk and a nice swim!
いい汗かいたぜ！
Worked up a good sweat!
お前！真ん丸がないどころか、ボスに怒られたのだ！
Why you...! Now only was there not a round thing, but Boss got angry at us!
怖かったのだ！
It was scary!
まあ、まあ。ラッキービーストなんて、
Now, now. In comparison to dinosaurs,
恐竜に比べたらかわいいもんだよ！
Lucky Beast is pretty cute!
キョーリュー？
Dyna-sore?
なんだか大変だったんだね！
Sounds like it was rough!
料理食べる？もうすぐできるよ！
Wanna eat? It's almost ready!
食べます、食べます。
Yes, yes, we'll eat.
これが噂の、「料理」、ですか？
Is this the "cooking" of legend?
今日は、ほとんどサーバルちゃんが作ってくれたんですよ。
Serval-chan cooked most of everything tiday.
ふっふーん。
That's right!
かばん。味見をちゃんとしてね。
Kaban. Make sure to taste-test it.
いただこう。お腹がペコペコだよ。
Let us eat. I'm starving.
ジャパリまん持ってないの？あげようか？
Don't you guys have Japari buns? Should I give you some of mine?
いや、持ってるんだが…
No, we have some, just that...
食べさしてやりたいやつがいてな。
控えてるんだ。
なんだか雛鳥みたいね。
飲み込んで運べばよかったかもー。
なっ！？それはいいですねー！
ペンギンさんらしい運搬方法！
うへへ…一度ご馳走なりたいです…
うへへ…はははは…へへへへ…
何の事か分からないけど、
私は普通に貰う方がいいかな。
かばんは？今日どこに行ってたの？
今日は、アリツカゲラさんにお話を聞きに。
すごく勉強になりました！
蟻塚に寝るのは、難しいかもしれないけど、
既にある物を寝床に利用するのは、大事な事だね。
うわ！？
へぇ！？
すっかりボス恐怖症ね…
でもこのボスあまり怖くないね。
お話ができたら、他のボスも実は優しいのかも。
ところで、「まんまる」って、何なんだ？
ハカセに頼まれて、探しているのだ！
サプライズでねー。
道のりは長いよー。
こっちのこれも、サプライズだぜ！
そうなんだ！誰かを喜ばせるの？楽しみだね！
みんな、楽しそうですね！
あ、料理ができたよ！
食べよう、食べよう！
料理か。久しぶりだなぁ。しっしっしっし。
ありがとう、サーバルちゃん。
Thank you, Serval-chan.
かばん、味見をちゃんとしてね。
Kaban. Make sure to taste-test it.